Guide to the American Labor Conference on International Affairs Records TAM.038
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series I. Correspondence, 1941-1947, nd
  - "G", Mar 1943-May 27 1946 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:37
  - Gold, Mary Jayne, Jul 7, 1943-Jun 21, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:38
  - Golden, Clinton S., Dec 30, 1942-Jun 20, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:39
  - Goldsmith, Arthur, Aug 10, 1943-Jul 16, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:40
  - Green, John, Jul 26, 1943-Mar 29, 1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:41
  - Greer, Guy, May 11, 1943-Aug 10, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:42
  - "H", Feb 5, 1943-Sep 12, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:43
  - "H", Oct 9, 1944-Jul 12, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Heine, B. F., Nov 14, 1941-Dec 1943 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:44
  - Heine, B. F., Feb 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Heine, B. F., Jan 1945-Apr 30, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Heine, B. F., May 4, 1945-Dec 5, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Herling, John S., Apr 5, 1944-Nov 4, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:45
  - Hebrew Sheltering and Immigrant Aid Society and HIAS-ICA Emigration Association, Feb 5, 1944-Aug 4, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:46
  - Hollander, Louis, Dec 19, 1942-Dec 21, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:47
  - "I", Mar 4, 1943-Apr 25, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:48
  - "I", May 8, 1944-Dec 20, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "I", Jan 29, 1945-Apr 9, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, Mar 4, 1943-Dec 17, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:49
  - International Labor Conference, Apr 22, 1944-May 1944 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:50
  - International Labour Office, Jun 1943-Dec 5, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:51
  - International Labour Review, Oct 20, 1943-Dec 3, 1945 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:52
  - The American Association for an International Office for Education, Jun 28, 1944-May 29, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:53
  - International Postwar Problems, Dec 6, 1943-Apr 1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 20: Frame XVI:A:54
  - International Postwar Problems, Sep 1943-Dec 1944 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:54
  - International Postwar Problems, Jan 1945-Jul 10, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - International Rescue and Relief Committee, Dec 22, 1943-Jun 19, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:55
  - International Study Center, Apr 9, 1943-Jan 2, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:56
  - "J", Sep 8, 1943-Mar 15, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:57
  - "K", Mar 17, 1943-Jan 7, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:58
  - Kenyon, Dorothy, Oct 11, 1944-Apr 26, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:59
  - "L", Feb 4, 1943-Jun 29, 1944 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:60
  - "L", Jul 1944-Feb 1945 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "L", Mar 1945-May 7, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lange, Oscar, Dec 7, 1942-Jan 16, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:61
  - Lieberman, Elias, Jan 19, 1943-Apr 24, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:62
  - "M", Dec 30, 1942-Oct 31, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:63
  - "M", Nov 1, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Murray, Philip, Jun 2, 1944-Feb 9, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:64
  - "N", Mar 15, 1943-Dec 28, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:65
  - "N", Jan 2, 1945-Dec 6, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - National Planning Association, Jun 25, 1943-Jun 13, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:66
  - The New Republic, Oct 19, 1943-Apr 16, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:67
  - Non-Partisan League, Apr 29, 1943-Oct 31, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:68
  - Non-Partisan Council to Win The Peace, Nov 1, 1944-May 8, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:69
  - "O", Sep 30, 1943-Jan 7, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:70
  - Office of War Information, Feb 17, 1943-Apr 23, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:71
  - "P", Feb 15, 1943-Jun 27, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 21: Frame XVI:A:72
  - "P", Jul 10, 1944-Apr 1945 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - "P", May 1945-Dec 2, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Pollaczek, Gustave, May 25, 1944-Mar 18, 1946 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:73
  - "Q", Oct 21, 1943-Dec 4, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:74
  - "R", Mar 15, 1943-Jul 1944 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:75
  - "R", Aug 1944-Jan 1945 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "R", Apr 1945-Jul 8, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reuther, Walter P., Feb 16, 1943-Nov 1, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:76
  - "S", Jan 28, 1943-May 1944 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:77
  - "S", Jun 1944 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "S", Jan 1945-Jun 30, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - "S", Jul 3, 1945-Jan 8, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Staal, Ad., Nov 9, 1943-Jul 25, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:78
  - Sollmann, William F., Jul 28, 1943-Feb 26, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:79
  - "T", Mar 15, 1943-Dec 28, 1944 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:80
  - "T", Jan 1945-Jan 13, 2947 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Telegrams, Jan 27, 1943-Mar 23, 1946, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:81
  - Thank You Notes, Mar 12, 1945-Nov 12, 1945 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:82
  - Twentieth Century Fund, Feb 1, 1943-May 16, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:83
  - "U", Sep 8, 1943-Apr 1945 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:84
  - "U", May 1945-Dec 11, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Union for Democratic Action, Foreign Policy Committee, Oct 4, 1943-Dec 4, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:85
  - U. S. Department of Commerce, Mar 10, 1943-Aug 6, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:86
  - U. S. Department of State, Nov 30, 1943-Apr 1946 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:87
  - U. S. Department of the Treasury, Apar 21, 1943-Oct 11, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:88
  - "V", Nov 23, 1943-Jul 24, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:89
  - "W", Feb 27, 1943-May 24, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:90
  - "W", Jun 12, 1944-Dec 1944 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - "W", Jan 1945-Aug 6, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Wachenheim, Hedwig, Jan 31, 1944-Apr 28, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 22: Frame XVI:A:91
  - Walsh, J. Raymond, Feb 5, 1943-Aug 1945 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:92
  - Welt, Frederick, Dec 17, 1943-Jul 26, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:93
  - Willie, Werner, Dec 17, 1943-Jul 26, 1944 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:94
  - Woll, Matthew, Dec 28, 1942-Aug 1944 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:95
  - Woll, Matthew, Sep 1944-Jul 12, 1946 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson Memorial Library, Sep 29, 1943-Dec 27, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:96
  - Workers Defense League, Oct 30, 1943-Dec 13, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:97
  - Woytinsky, Vladimir, Dec 15, 1942-Nov 9, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:98
  - Writers' War Board, Feb 17, 1944-Apr 26, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:99
  - Wunderlich, Frieda, Mar 15, 1943-Apr 2, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:100
  - "XYZ", Jan 25, 1944-Jan 6, 1947 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:101
  - Zaritsky, Max, Dec 10, 1942-Jul 6, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:102
  - Zimmerman, Charles, Dec 8, 1942-Feb 21, 1946 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:A:103
- Series II. Office Files, 1940-1947, nd
  - ABC of World Peace, Oct 22, 1943-Nov 3, 1943, undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:1
  - AFL, Mar 10, 1943-Mar 27, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:2
  - AFL Meeting: Draft Resolution, Apr 12, 1944-Apr 13, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:3
  - AFL Postwar Planning Committee, Jan 1943-Jul 20, 1944, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:4
  - American Labor Conference: By-Laws, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:5
  - American Writers Association, Sep 11, 1946-Nov 1946 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:6
  - Biographical Data for Contributor's Box for Postwar Problems, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:7
  - Broadcasts, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:8
  - The Case Against Falangist Spain, Apr 7, 1942, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:9
  - Comments on ALCIA Publications (via correspondence), Apr 25, 1944-May 1946 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:10
  - Commission on Education, Jun 2, 1944-Jun 27, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:11
  - Commission on Labor Questions, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:12
  - Commission on Political Questions, Oct 18, 1943, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:13
  - Comments on ALCIA Publications (published), 1940s (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Comments on ALCIA Publications (published), 1940s (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - ALCIA Conference, Jun 12, 1943: Correspondence, Feb 2, 1943-Dec 1, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:14
  - ALCIA Conference Jun 12, 1943: Speeches (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:15
  - ALCIA Conference, November 1943: Correspondence, Nov 4, 1943-Nov 22, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:16
  - ALCIA Conference, 16 December 1944: Correspondence, Oct 5, 1944-Jan 3, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:17
  - ALCIA Conference, 16 December 1944: Finances, Dec 14, 1944-Nov 1946 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:18
  - ALCIA Conference, 16 December 1944: Press Releases, Dec 4, 1944-Dec 16, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:19
  - ALCIA Conference, 16 December 1944: Printing and Promotion, Dec 1, 1944-Dec 15, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:20
  - ALCIA Conference, 16 December 1944: Proceedings, undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:21
  - ALCIA Conference, 12 January 1946: Correspon­dence, Dec 18, 1945-Jan 27, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:22
  - ALCIA Conference, 12 January 1946: Proceedings, undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:23
  - Connally Resolution, Oct 1943 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:24
  - Council for a Democratic Germany, Apr 1944-May 1944 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:25
  - Courses, Sep 9, 1943-Dec 1943 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:26
  - Currency Plans, Apr 5, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:27
  - Directories & Address Books, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Daily Worker Clippings, 1944 -, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Economic Section: Minutes, Jan 30, 1943 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:28
  - Emmet, Christopher, Jul 20, 1944-Dec 9, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:29
  - Finances, Miscellaneous, Dec 1, 1942-Jan 15, 1947 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:30
  - Finances, Accounts Payable, Jul 1, 1944-Oct 22, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:31
  - Finances, Payroll, Nov 8, 1944-Feb 25, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:32
  - Finances, Reports, Jan 1, 1945-Jan 1, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:33
  - Finances, Taxes, Aug 1, 1944-Sep 11, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:34
  - Fitch, Geraldine, May 22, 1944-May 19, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:35
  - Fund Raising, Jan 24, 1944-Jun 28, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:36
  - General Giraud, Jul 26, 1940 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:37
  - Germany, undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 23: Frame XVI:B:38
  - Hagan, Paul, "Deutschland Nach Hitler: Um. Die Volkndung Der Demokratischen Revolution", May 1943 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:39
  - Hansen, Alvin, Jun 12, 1943-Mar 23, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:40
  - Incorporation, Jan 1, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:41
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, Oct 8, 1942-Dec 1946 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:42
  - Labor Section, Minutes, Jan 18, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:43
  - Liberal Party, May 18, 1944-Apr 9, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:44
  - Liberal and Labor Committee, Program Committee, Apr 29, 1944-May 1944 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:45
  - Finances, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Lists, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - ALCIA Members (Paid), Jan 3, 1945-Jul 5, 1945, undated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:46
  - Membership Campaign Letters, undated (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:47
  - Memos, Dec 17, 1943-Dec 20, 1943 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:48
  - Newspaper Clippings on ALCIA, Dec 8, 1944-Jan 20, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:49
  - News Releases, Feb 8, 1944, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:50
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Economic Series Contains: Lerner, Abba P., "The Disposal of Government Owned Plants After the War," Occasional Paper No. 1, 2 December 1943. 20pp. - "Comments on 'The United States in the World Economy'," occasional Paper No. 2, 27 December 1943. 22pp. - Halasi, Albert, "The Baruch Report and Economic Welfare in the Post-Reconversion Period," Occasional Paper No. 3, May 1944. 26pp. -, "Tax Reduction in 1945," Occasional Paper No. 4, October 1945.11pp., Oct 8, 1943-Oct 1945 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:51
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Economic Series Contains: Lerner, Abba P., "The Disposal of Government Owned Plants After the War," Occasional Paper No. 1, 2 December 1943. 20pp. - "Comments on 'The United States in the World Economy'," occasional Paper No. 2, 27 December 1943. 22pp. - Halasi, Albert, "The Baruch Report and Economic Welfare in the Post-Reconversion Period," Occasional Paper No. 3, May 1944. 26pp. -, "Tax Reduction in 1945," Occasional Paper No. 4, October 1945.11pp., Oct 8, 1943-Oct 1945 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Educational Series Contains: - Wille, Werner, "A Survey of Educational Planning in the United States and Various Other Countries," Occasional Paper No. 1, February 1944. 59pp., Feb 1944 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:52
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Labor Series Contains: Schwarz, Solomon, "The Reforms of the International Labor organization," occasional Paper No. 1, 16 pp., April 1944., Apr 1944 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:53
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Monetary Series Contains: - Halasi, Albert, "Comments on the Revised White Plan," Occasional Paper No. 2, 19 November 1943. l5pp. - Halasi, Albert, "The United Nations Bank for Reconstruction and Development: Comments on the 'Guiding Prin­ciples'," occasional Paper No. 3, 7 pp., Nov 22, 1943. - Halasi, Albert, "The United Nations Bank for Reconstruction and Development: Comments on the 'Preliminary Draft Outline', " Occasional Paper No. 4, 7 pp., Dec15, 1943 - Halasi, Albert, "Bretton Woods and Full Employment," Occasional Paper No. 5, 59 pp., March 1945, Nov 19, 1943-Mar 1945 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:54
  - ALCIA Occasional Papers, Political Series Contains: - Denicke, George, "The Three Powers Conference in Moscow," occasional Paper No. 1, 10 pp., Nov 8, 1943 - Denicke, George, "A Critical Examination of the Dunbarton Oaks Proposals," Occasional Paper No. 2, 14 pp., April 1945, Nov 1943-Apr 1945 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:55
  - ALCIA Pamphlets Contains: - Ibanez, Bernardo. What the Workers Expect of the International Labor Organization. New York: American Labor Conference on International Affairs, 18 pp., 1944. - Mitchell, Broadus and Hauser, Francis L. Labor's Stake in Bretton Woods. New York: American Labor Conference on International Affairs, 15 pp., 1945, 1944-1945 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:56
  - Confidential Speeches by Joseph H. Ball, William Green, Robert M. MacIver, Dec 16, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Braunthal, Alfred, "Safeguards Against Oppressive Labor Conditions in Backward Countries," - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Feb 1944 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:57
  - Report on the discussion at the Treasury Depart­ment - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Jan 5, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:58
  - Dekock, Jules, "Belgian Trade Unionism in the Postwar Era," ll pp. (2 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:59
  - De Los Rios (Rough Draft) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:60
  - Denicke, George, "Recent Trends in the Literature of Postwar Planning," l8pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:61
  - Elvin, Herbert L. Contains: - "Tax Reduction in 1945," l0 pp. (2 copies) - Elvin, Herbert L., "The British Soldier and the Post-War World," nd. 5pp. - "Papers drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", 1945, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:62
  - "The Financial Aspects of International Trade in Its Relationship to Prosperity in the U.S.," 26pp. (2 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:63
  - Fraenkel, Ernst, "Freedom of Association," 4pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Feb 1944 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:64
  - Halasi, Albert, Manuscripts Contains: - Halasi, Albert, "Bretton Woods and Full Employment," January 1945. ll pp. (2 copies) - Halasi, Albert, "Comments on the Revised White Plan," nd. l5pp. (2 copies) - Halasi, Albert, "Comments on Three Memoranda on the Postwar Tax System," nd. l5pp. (3 copies) - Halasi, Albert, "The Contribution of the Bretton Woods Agreements to Full Employment," nd. 33pp. - Halasi, Albert, "A Common Program for Business and Labor," nd. 23pp. (2 copies) - Halasi, Albert, "Note on the Subsistence of the German People After the War," February 1945. 5pp. - Halasi, Albert, "Should Germany Be Deprived of Her Industry? Comments on the Baruch Report," nd. l3pp. - "Papers drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Jan 1945-Feb 1945 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:65
  - Hansen, Alvin, "The Postwar Reemployment Problem," ll pp. (2 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Jun 1943 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:66
  - "Labor's International Rights," 28pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:67
  - Lerner, Abba P., "The Government-Owned Plants -What To Do With Them?" 7pp. + memo - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Nov 16, 1943 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:68
  - Neisser, Hans, "The Problem of Reparations," 4pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Feb 1944 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:69
  - Papanek, Ernst, Rough drafts, - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Mar 1944 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:70
  - Reuther, Walter, Material for IPP article, - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:71
  - Schreider, Eugene, "Workers Resistance in France," 22pp. (2 copies-1 in French) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Apr 5, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:72
  - Schwarz, Solomon, "The Reform of the International Labor organizations," Studies in Postwar Recon­struction No. 3, l2 pp. (4 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", Mar 1944 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:73
  - Sluyser, Meyer, "The Dutch Working Class Movement During the German Occupation," 8pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 13)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:74
  - "Statement on Labor's Attitude Towards the Pro­posal for the Establishment of an International Stabilization Fund," 5pp. (3 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 14)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:75
  - "Suggestions for Improving the Draft Proposal for the Establishment of a World Bank," 2pp. (3 copies) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 15)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:76
  - Vignaux, Paul, "The French Trade Union Movement Since the Armistice of 1940," l4pp. (4 copies-1 in French) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:77
  - Vignaux, Paul, "Rebuild the French Labor Movement," 5pp. (3 copies-1 in French) - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:78
  - Vishniak, Mark, "Political Security and World Organization, Lessons of the Failure of the League of Nations," incomplete. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:79
  - Wachenheim, Hedwig, [Study on Germany in the postwar period], 44pp. nd - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:80
  - Wachenheim, Hedwig,, "The Revival of the German Labor Movement After the War," 26pp. - "Paper drafted for research use by ALCIA officials", undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
    Film R-7124, Reel 24: Frame XVI:B:81